<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Educational on Supriya Dutta</title>
    <link>/categories/educational/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Educational on Supriya Dutta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 15:20:40 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/educational/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Eat-o-pia - a multiplayer phy-gital game</title>
      <link>/stories/eatopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 15:20:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/stories/eatopia/</guid>
      <description>INTRODUCTION During our Game Design module at IDC School of Design, we – a group of four participants – wanted to explore the the usage of Games in sharing knowledge of Food chain through hybrid or phy-gital games. To complete our exploratory project were allotted a time period of 1 week. DATA COLLECTION For this project we decided to take the help of NCERT books (National Council of Educational Research and Training) designed for students of Central board of Secondary Education India, as our primary resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eat-o-pia - a multiplayer phy-gital game</title>
      <link>/archives/eatopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 15:20:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/archives/eatopia/</guid>
      <description>Overview BACKGROUNDDuring our Game Design module at IDC School of Design, we – a group of four participants – wanted to explore the usage of Games in sharing knowledge of Food chain through hybrid or phy-gital games. To complete our exploratory project were allotted a time period of 1 week.
OBJECTIVEThis project&amp;rsquo;s main goals were to encourage player interaction and raise players&amp;rsquo; awareness of the interdependence and flow of energy among living things in our environment through an interactive game world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
