<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interaction Design on Supriya Dutta</title>
    <link>/categories/interaction-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interaction Design on Supriya Dutta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 16:23:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/interaction-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nature&#39;s palette - a playful adventure</title>
      <link>/posts/naturespalette/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 16:23:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/naturespalette/</guid>
      <description>Overview BACKGROUNDCan we foster curiosity in children about our natural environment? During the Interaction Design module at IDC School of Design, we (our group had 4 participants) were assigned a project - nudge children to explore their natural environment more, with one constraint - through the use of Colours.
PRODUCT DETAILSThrough the use of colours and textures, the Nature’s Palette app aims to help kids connect with their surroundings. Together, kids explore their environment and take photos of the many colours and textures they encounter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature&#39;s palette - a playful adventure</title>
      <link>/stories/naturespalette/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 16:23:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/stories/naturespalette/</guid>
      <description>INTRODUCTION Can we foster curiosity in children about our natural environment?During the Interaction Design module at IDC School of Design, we (our group had 4 participants) were assigned a project - nudge children to explore their natural environment more, with one constraint - through the use of Colours.
But, how do we
Ensure that children become familiar with unfamiliar environment? Nudge children to use the platform? Encourage collaborative learning? RESEARCH We started our research on twe areas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
