<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dataviz on Supriya Dutta</title>
    <link>/categories/dataviz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dataviz on Supriya Dutta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 16:08:20 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/dataviz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing radiology data - Predible health report</title>
      <link>/posts/predible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 16:08:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/predible/</guid>
      <description>Predible Health is an AI startup. They work with Artificial Intelligence to draw out information from Radiology data. We collaborated on a project to create physical reports for the users – Pulmonologist, radiologist, and patients. The objective of the project was to find an effective way of representing the Lung CT Scan data into a medical report, specially catered to our target users. The data we wanted to present was divided into three sections: Nodule analysis data, Low Attenuation analysis data, and High Attenuation analysis data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>600 years of Ahom Kingdom</title>
      <link>/posts/ahoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 22:13:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ahoms/</guid>
      <description>The Ahom dynasty was the most celebrated in Assam&amp;rsquo;s history. With a successful reign of 600 years they were able to enrich Assam with agriculture, architecture, cultural richness and different scientific interventions. Ahoms were the descendants of Tai or Shan race who came from Mungmao, currently in Yunan province of China. They came to Brahmaputra Valley of North East India in 1228. The kingdom of Ahoms established during 13th century entails an important part of the Assamese history.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
