<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on Supriya Dutta</title>
    <link>/categories/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on Supriya Dutta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 22:13:04 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>600 years of Ahom Kingdom - a visual data narrative</title>
      <link>/posts/ahoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 22:13:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ahoms/</guid>
      <description>Overview BACKGROUNDThe Ahom dynasty was the most celebrated in Assam’s history. With a successful reign of 600 years they were able to enrich Assam with agriculture, architecture, cultural richness and different scientific interventions. Ahoms were the descendants of Tai or Shan race who came from Mungmao, currently in Yunan province of China. They came to Brahmaputra Valley of North East India in 1228. The kingdom of Ahoms established during 13th century entails an important part of the Assamese history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>600 years of Ahom Kingdom - a visual data narrative</title>
      <link>/stories/ahoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 22:13:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/stories/ahoms/</guid>
      <description>The Ahom dynasty was the most celebrated in Assam&amp;rsquo;s history. With a successful reign of 600 years they were able to enrich Assam with agriculture, architecture, cultural richness and different scientific interventions. Ahoms were the descendants of Tai or Shan race who came from Mungmao, currently in Yunan province of China. They came to Brahmaputra Valley of North East India in 1228. The kingdom of Ahoms established during 13th century entails an important part of the Assamese history.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
