<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Game Design on Supriya Dutta</title>
    <link>/categories/game-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Game Design on Supriya Dutta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 16:23:14 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/game-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zuci - A Phy-gital multiplayer turn based strategy game</title>
      <link>/posts/zuci/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 16:23:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/zuci/</guid>
      <description>INTRODUCTION Folk musical instruments bind one&amp;rsquo;s community together. Within a community, each instrument has its own specific use, place and time to be played. However, with the popularization of new electronic musical instruments and music, the audience base of traditional folk musical instruments have decreased considerably.
To gather more information about the same, we met with Brahmaputra cultural Foundation(BCF), an NGO who is working on conserving folk musical instruments of the North-eastern states of India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A study: Determine the efficacy of three medium of instructions in sharing knowledge of Folk musical instruments</title>
      <link>/posts/reszuci/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 15:20:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/reszuci/</guid>
      <description>OVERVIEW Background Traditional folk musical instrumentsare facing extinctionin many parts of India due to decrease in its user base. The purposeof this study was to determine an effective medium to introduce these musicalinstruments: their construction process, sounds and events they are used at, to a younger audience, in order to create a future user baseof individuals with better understanding of the same.
Objective Through this study we aim to introduce different mediums of instruction to children above age of 8 years and observe how they respond to them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
